有谁能帮帮我, 求求你们
Somebody help me, please.
我要窒息了
I'm suffocating!
快点, 有谁能帮帮我...
Quickly! Somebody help me, please!
我要窒息了
I'm suffocating!
帮帮我, 求求你们!
Help me! Please!
那, 但我的弟弟怎么办?
Yeah, but what about me brother?
恐怕我现在有更严重的情况要查, 小姐
I'm afraid I've got something
more serious to look into first, Miss.
如果这个年轻人说的是实情
If this young man's telling the truth,
我的一个同事已经被谋害了
a colleague of mine's been murdered.
- 博士, 这个人有话和你说  - 哦, 是谁?
- Doctor, this man wants to talk to you. - Oh, Who is he?
就是这位, 先生
There you are, sir.
Crossland 督察, 苏格兰场
"Detective Inspector Crossland. Scotland Yard. "
- 我把一切都告诉他了  - 你见过这个人吗?
- I told him everything.
- Have you ever seen that man?
就是我们在变色龙机库发现的那个人!
Well, that's the man we found in the Chameleon Tours hangar.
博士的尸体呢, 在哪儿
The Doctor's body. Where is it?
他...逃走了
He... escaped.
他的智力远在那些普通人之上
His intelligence is far above normal beings.
也在你之上, 估计
Above YOURS, perhaps
我得走了, 去苏黎世的飞机已经准备起飞了
I must leave. The flight to Zurich is ready to take off.
你就留在这里
You will remain here.
- 为什么目的?  - 弥补你的无能
- For what purpose? - To atone for your incompetence.
博士必须死, 你必须搞定
The Doctor must die, and you must do it.
好了, 博士, 我们去见总指挥
All right then, Doctor, we'll go and see the commandant.
我想让他听听你的故事
I want him to hear your story.
但是, 上一次他并没有太相信
Well, he wasn't very impressed with it the last time.
这一次, 他会相信你
This time, he's gonna believe you.
好吧, 如果你觉得
Well, if you think so.
Jamie, 待在这里盯着柜台, 我们不会很久
Jamie, stay here and keep an eye on the kiosk.
We shan't be long.
别担心你的弟弟, 小姐. 我们会替你找到他
Don't worry about your brother, Miss.
We'll find him for you.
- 这个督察以后会很出色的!   - 但他相信我们
- A fat lot of good that inspector's going to be!
- But he believes us.
哦, 是, 不过那也不代表他肯定会采取什么措施
Oh, year, but that doesn't mean to say
he's going to do anything.
我想我得去那个变色龙机库看一遭
I think I'll go and have a look
round that Chameleon hangar.
你自己可不行
Not by yourself.
是啊, 我觉得要是有位男士陪我去, 肯定会好些
Well, I suppose it would be better
if I had a man with me.
是, 如果博士没让我盯着这个地方就好了
Aye. If only the Doctor hadn't told me
to watch this place.
哦, 你是不是总是按别人的吩咐做事?
Oh, do you always do everything you're told?
不是, 但是博士信任我
No, but the Doctor trusts me.
哦, 这就是你的问题了, 对不?
Yeah, that's your trouble, isn't it!
好吧, 待在这里
All right, stay here.
毕竟, 他们最多也只能杀了我, 拜拜
After all, they can only murder me. Ta-ra.
不, 等等
No, wait a minute.
我估计这里也不会有什么情况, 你觉得呢?
I don't suppose anything will happen here, do you?
他们都已经关掉柜台了, 所以不太可能
Since they closed the kiosk, so it's hardly likely.
而且我们不会耽误很久, 对吧?
And we won't be long, will we?
这就取决于我们能发现什么. 快走吧, 小子
Well, that depends on what we find. Come on, kid.
不管怎么, 你需要我给你带路
In any case, you need me
to show you the way there!
好了好了, 我接受你发现了一具尸体
All right, all right.
I'll accept that you found a body,
但我还是想知道你从哪里来的, 为什么没有护照
but I still want to know where you come from
and why you have no passport.
- 显然这不重要吧?   - 违反法律不可能不重要!
- Surely that's unimportant?
- It is not unimportant to break the law!
先生, 我觉得我们还是得让他先说说
Sir, I think we'll have to let him
tell us in his own way.
- 好吧, 简短一点  - 谢谢你
- Very well. Make it brief.  Thank you.
我刚刚去变色龙观光游的机库进行了一番搜索
I have just carried out a search
of the Chameleon Tours hangar.
在一个行李箱里面, 我们找到了一个男人的躯体
In a packing case, I found the body of a man.
你没告诉我这个, 博士. 又一个人死了?
You never told me that, Doctor.
Another dead man?
没死, 他处于一种神志不清的状态, 一种昏迷
No, he was in a stupefied state, a sort of coma.
- 这个人是谁?   - 我不知道他的名字
- Who's this one?
- I don't know his name.
但我有种感觉, 他是你的雇员之一
But I have a feeling he's one of your employees.
- 噢, 真的?  - 事实上, 我觉得他可能就在这里
- Oh, indeed?
- In fact, I think he may be in here.
滑行, 沿南部滑行路, 前往27号起飞跑道
Taxi, following southern taxi way
for departure runway 27...
- 你知道这是什么吗?  - 我觉得它像支钢笔
- Do you know what this is?
- It looks like a fountain pen to me.
事情并不总是看起来的那样. 小心, 它很危险!
Things are not always what they seem.
Careful! It's dangerous.
变色龙观光游也不像它看起来那样
Chameleon Tours are not quite what they seem either.
And what's your theory?
那你的理论是什么?
等你听了, 恐怕你不会相信
I'm afraid you won't believe it
when you hear it....
首先, Gascoigne 督察被一把射线枪谋杀了
First, Inspector Gascoigne
was murdered with a ray gun.
一把射线枪?
A ray gun?
一种在这个地球上还没被研发出来的武器
A weapon that has not yet
been developed on this Earth.
- 哦, 真的吗?   - 你看, 我就知道你不会相信我
- Oh, really!
- You see, I knew you wouldn't believe it.
不, 请耐心点, 先生. 我们在试着理解你说的
No, now be patient, sir.
We are trying to understand you.
很好. 然后, 我相信变色龙观光游
Very well. Next, I believe Chameleon Tours
- 只不过是一个幌子, 一个掩护 - 掩护什么?
- to be merely a front - a cover.
- For what?
掩护他们大规模绑架年轻人
For the mass kidnapping of young people.
而所有这些都发生在我的机场?
And is all this supposed
to be taking place in my airport?
- 是的, 就在当下!   - 这可真够了!
- Yes. At this very moment.
- That's quite enough!
你就不能把这家伙关起来吗?
Can't you take that fellow into custody?
很抱歉, 先生. 但你知道他没有违反任何法律
Well, I'm very sorry, sir,
but you know he hasn't broken any law.
除非是出入境方面的问题, 那可不是我的职责范围
except for this immigration business,
and that's not my responsibility.
- Brian Briggs 是你的职责范围  - 那又是谁?
- Brian Briggs IS your responsibility!
- Who is he?
他是个年轻人, 参加了变色龙观光游, 然后消失了!
He's a young man who went on
the Chameleon tour and vanished.
得了, 博士, 等一下. 这一点我们还没有确认
Come on Doctor, wait a minute.
We're not certain of that yet.
四处都找不到他, 也找不到我的两朋友
Well, he's nowhere to be found,
and neither are my two friends,
这在我看来就证实了我的观点——
which in mind proves my point:
变色龙观光游是个幌子, 就为了绑架年轻人
Chameleon Tours are a cover
for the abducting of young people.
敢问他们被带到哪里去了?
And just where do you think they're taking them?
你看, 从我已经呈现的事实来看
Well, in view of the facts that I've already presented
射线枪, 这种笔, 以及其它一两个东西
the ray gun, this pen,
and one or two other things -
我想我们在对付的人, 不是来自这个星球!
I think we're dealing with people
who are not from this planet.
这也没能回答我的问——你刚才说什么?
That hardly answers my que...
What did you say?!
你看, 我就知道你不信我
You see, I knew you wouldn't believe me.
这完完全全是胡说八道!
This is absolute arrant nonsense!
你看, 博士, 我觉得应该提供一些证据来支撑这些说法
Look, Doctor, I think you ought to
produce some evidence to support all this.
- 证据? 这支笔怎么说?   - 一只笔! 你管这叫证据?
- Evidence? What about this pen?
- A pen! Do you call that evidence?
我来给你演示一下
I'll demonstrate it for you.
打扰了
Excuse me.
- 你介意帮我们一下吗?   - 我没明白
- Would you mind helping us?
- I don't understand.
你能不能把这个杯子举在面前?
Could you hold this cup out in front of you?
很好
Very well.
- 也许你以前见过这个?   - 没有. 啊!
- Perhaps you've seen one of these before?
- No. Agh!
它变成冰了!
It's turned to ice!
你管这个叫胡说八道?
Do you call that arrant nonsense?
亲爱的妈妈爸爸, 已经安全抵达黑森林了
"Dear Mum and Dad.
Have arrived safely in the Black Forest."
我会很快再写给你们, 爱你们的 Tim
"Will write again soon. Love, Tim. "
亲爱的爸爸, 我...
"Dear Dad, I... "
亲爱的妈妈...
"Dear Mum... "
Jamie!
Jamie! 你看我找到了什么
Jamie! Look what I've found.
这里至少有50张明信片
There must be 50 postcards here.
这肯定能让那位督察采取点什么行动了
That should make that inspector do something.
你说得对, 而且我知道去哪里找他
You're right, and I know where to find him.
你是个勇敢的小姑娘, 现在没时间向你致敬了
You're a brave wee lassie.
No time to greet now.
闪开! 有什么东西进我眼睛了. 走吧
Get off! I've got something in me eye. Come on.
我们往哪儿走?
Where are we going?
总指挥的办公室
The commandant's office.
博士, 这是你要的变色龙观光游后面的飞机排班表
Doctor, here are the remaining flight schedules
for Chameleon Tours you wanted.
- 这个小装置可真厉害  - 最好让我仔细检查一下, 先生
- What a nasty little device.
- I'd better get that checked over, sir.
- 什么情况?   - Samantha, 下来这边
- What the devil...   - Samantha, down here.
- 明信片, 快看!  - 我不会容忍有人乱闯控制室!
- Postcards! Look.
- I will not have my control room invaded!
- 有这些也不行吗?  - 你拿的是什么?
- Not even for these?
- What have you got there?
我想这是你要求的进一步证据, 督察
I think it's the further evidence
you required, Inspector.
对了...跟我想的一样
Yes... Just as I thought.
- 你在哪里拿到的?  - 在那个机库的办公室里
- Where did you get these?
- In the office in that hangar.
- 你明白这意味着什么吗?   - 规律已经很明显了
- You see what they mean?
- All falling into a pattern.
这个信封写的寄信地址是德国的某个地方
This envelope is addressed to somewhere in Germany.
还有, 德文的版本
Yeah. "Dem Chameleon Reisen, Freiberg."
That means Chameleon Tours.
你都在叨叨些什么?
Just what are you all talking about?
你瞧, 他们派发出这些卡片
You see, they give out these cards,
让这些孩子在出发之前就写给他们家里的父母
and get the kids to write home
to their parents before they go.
变色龙观光游的家伙就把这些卡片带上飞机
The Chameleon Tours lot take the cards abroad
然后他们把卡片寄回不列颠
and THEY post them back to Britain.
于是父母们就以为他们的孩子已经安全抵达了
So the parents think the children
have arrived safely.
博士, 你觉得他们身上发生了什么事情?
Doctor, what do you think happens to them?
不, 不, 这些都只不过是臆测
Now, now. This is all mere supposition!
噢, 对你来说, 也许吧
Oh, to you, maybe,
但这里面其中一个孩子恰巧就是我弟弟
but one of those kids
happens to be my brother.
你弟弟?
Your brother?
是, 先生, 就是这位小姐的弟弟失踪了
Aye, sir. This is the young lady
whose brother's missing
而且你看, 她的确收到了一张她弟弟从罗马寄来的卡片
and you see, she did get a card from him in Rome.
可是为什么有谁会绑架这些年轻人呢?
But why would anyone want
to abduct these young people?
要是我们知道了这个, 我们就不会干坐在这里了
Well, if we knew that, we wouldn't be sitting here.
督察, 我能跟你说句话吗?
Inspector, can I have a word with you?
你不觉得这家伙有点不正常吗, 对不?
You don't think this fellow's
a little unbalanced, do you?
哦, 也许是有点不循规蹈矩, 先生
Oh maybe a wee bit unorthodox, sir.
但毕竟, 到目前为止是他给了我们唯一的线索
But after all, he's given us
the only lead we've got so far.
如果你愿意, 不如放手让他干
If you could, just see your way to giving him a free hand.
- 让他干?  - 只是四处摸索一下, 先生
- A free hand? - Just to poke around a little bit, sir.
你觉得安全吗, 让这个家伙在机场乱窜?
Do you think it's safe to
let the fellow roam around the airport?
你可以依靠我们来盯着他, 先生
You can rely on us to keep an eye on him, sir.
好吧, 但记在你的头上
All right, but on your head be it.
我自己会去调查变色龙观光游
I personally will investigate Chameleon Tours
如果发现什么, 也会回报给你
then I'll report back to you
if I've found out anything.
但于此同时, 你尽量让一切照常运转, 你明白吗?
But in the meantime, if you could just keep
everything going as normal, you understand?
- 我们不想让他们听到任何风吹草动  - 不, 不会
- We don't want them to get wind of anything.
- No, no, no, no, no.
博士, 我给你在机场12个小时的自由时间, 愿老天帮我
Doctor, I'm giving you the freedom
of the airport for 12 hours, heaven help me.
等12个小时结束, 我期望你带着点真正的证据回到这里来
At the end of that time, I shall expect you
back here with some real facts this time.
谢谢你, 总指挥
Thank you, Commandant.
- 他们信了那个博士了吗?   - 我不知道
- Did they believe the Doctor?
- I don't know.
- 什么意思?   - 我想他怀疑上我了
- What do you mean?
- I think he suspects me.
他朝我打开了我们的一个武器, 迫使我跑开了
He turned one of our own weapons on me.
Forced me to leave.
你个笨蛋, 你应该待着不动的
You fool. You should have stayed.
现在, 我们没法知道他到底发现了多少了
Now, we do not know
how much he has discovered.
即使他发现了我们的秘密任务, 他们也不会相信他的
Even if he has discovered the secret
of our mission, they won't believe him.
这些地球人的脑子想不了那么远
These Earth minds cannot stretch that far.
当然, 事实远非他们的智力所能想到, 除了博士
Of course, the truth is beyond their
intelligence, except for that Doctor.
我知道他在那里, 我可以杀了他
I know where he is. I could kill him.
你是要去, 不过不能让你自己有危险
You're going to, but not at the risk
of your own safety.
我们还需要你待在航空控制塔台
We still need you in Air Traffic Control.
带上这个, 贴到他身上
Take this. Attach it to him.
等你搞好了, 我就可以用这个激活这个装置
When you're ready, I shall
activate the mechanism with this.
- 这就可以一劳永逸解决他  - 很好
- That should put paid to him once and for all.
- Very well.
别耽误
Don't delay.
我要他在 Blade 队长回来之前就死了
I want him dead before Captain Blade returns.
博士...
Doctor...
- 我给你和你两个朋友做了通行证  - 谢谢你
- I've made out a pass for you and your two friends.
- Thank you.
抱歉, 先生. 有一架变色龙的航班进来了
Excuse me, sir. There's a Chameleon
flight coming in now.
ADSXL 呼叫盖特威克机场塔台
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima
calling Gatwick Airport Control.
盖特威克塔台呼叫ADSXL航班
Gatwick Control to
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
盖特威克塔台呼叫ADSXL航班
Gatwick Control to
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
我现在告诉你航向
I will now give you your heading.
- 他们一天有多少航班?   - 七到八个
- How many flights do they use a day?
- Seven or eight.
- 他们有几架飞机?  - 四架
- How many planes do they use?
- Four.
我可以查到他们的注册号, 如果你需要的话
I could get their registration numbers if you like.
为什么问这个?
Why do you ask?
一天八个航班却只有四架飞机, 这正常吗?
Eight flights a day and only four planes.
Is that normal?
正常, 只要他们周转得快
Yes. They have a very quick turnaround.
我是说, 毕竟他们只有短途航线
I mean, after all they're only on short haul flights
你知道的, 都是些旅游胜地, /
You know, all the holiday centres.
西班牙, 罗马, 雅典, 黑森林
Spain, Rome, Athens, the Black Forest.
- Jean, 冬天的排班表在哪里  - 抱歉
- Jean, where's the file on winter schedules.
- Excuse me.
- 哪个是变色龙的飞机  - 哦, 就那个, 先生
- Which is the Chameleon plane?
- Oh that one, sir.
你看, 他正在 Dunsfold 左转弯
Look, he's turning left at Dunsfold.
我会告诉他在Epsom等待, 直到我给出降落许可
I shall hold him now over Epsom
until I can give him landing clearance.
- 你们雷达的有效范围是多少?   - 130英里, 怎么了?
- What's the range of your radar?
- 130 miles. Why?
- 我在想他们的飞机什么时候出现  - 我不清楚, 先生
- I wondered when this plane first appeared.
- I've no idea, sir.
在他们开始呼叫之前我们看不到他们. 我先离开一下
We don't notice them until they start to call in.
Now excuse me a moment.
盖特威克塔台呼叫ADSXL航班
Gatwick Control
to Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
爬升到一万英尺, 在 Epsom 管制区等待降落许可
Climb to 10,000 feet and hold in
Epsom control zone to await landing clearance.
ADSXL航班, 爬升到一万英尺, 就地等待
Alpha Delta Sierra X-ray Lima.
Climbing to 10,000 feet and holding.
起飞之后你们可以跟住他们多久?
How long do you hold them after take-off?
一旦他们离开盖特威克管制区, 我们跟他们就没关系了
Once they've left Gatwick Control Zone,
we've finished with them.
我明白了, 那就意味着他们可能去任何地方
I see. That means they might be anywhere.
你不是宁愿浪费你的12个小时四处乱窜吗, 还来打扰我的人?
Aren't you rather wasting your 12 hours
hanging around here, disturbing my people?
我觉得我一分钟都没有浪费
I don't think I've been wasting a minute,
但你非要我走的话, 我会走. Sam! Jamie!
but I'll go if you insist. Sam! Jamie!
- 抱歉  - 没事, 完全是我的错
- Sorry.  - It's all right. It's quite my fault.
- 我以前在什么地方没碰见过你吗?   - 我觉得没有
- Haven't I met you somewhere before?
- I don't think so.
你肯定有一个替身!
You must have a double!
打扰一下, 你是这里的经理吗?
Excuse me, are you the manager?
我负责订票, 有什么可以帮你的?
I'm looking after bookings. Can I help?
我要跟经理谈话
I'd rather like to speak to the manager...
- 我是位警官  - 我们有麻烦吗?
- I'm a police officer.  - Is there some trouble?
- 我想和负责人谈  - 那得找 Blade 机长
- I'd prefer to speak to the person in charge.
- That's Captain Blade.
他刚从一个航班返回了, 下一个航班马上又要出发
He's just returned from one flight,
taking off for another.
- 他这会儿真的很忙  - 也许我可以直接去飞机上?
- He's rather busy at the moment.
- Perhaps I could go out to the plane?
我得去看看. 请等一下
I'll have to see about that. Just a moment, please.
有个警探要见你
A detective wants to see you.
他怀疑什么了吗?
Does he suspect anything?
我不知道
I don't know.
好, 送他去飞机上吧, 我们来对付他
All right. Send him over to the plane.
We'll deal with him.
你确定就是这个房间, 博士?
Are you sure this is the right room, Doctor?
- Jamie, 你什么时候见我出过错?   - 真是!
- Jamie, have you ever known me to be mistaken?  - Aye!
- 嘿, 小心一点  - 什么?
- Hey. Now watch out.  - What?
毒气喷嘴就是从那面墙出来的
That's the wall the gas nozzles came out of.
但现在这里什么也没有了
There's nothing here now.
你说得对
You're right.
这很高明, 非常高明
That's clever, very clever.
哦, 好了, 这就变得简单了
Oh, well, it makes life simpler for us.
看, 我定住的那个人是从这附近出来的
Now, the man I froze came from here somewhere.
是, 有可能 - 一堵实墙啊
Aye, he would - a solid wall
这堵实墙的某个地方, 有一道门
Somewhere in that solid wall, there's a door.
应该是. 我们还是没有找到 Ben 和 Polly
Aye, and we still haven't found Ben and Polly.
- 你觉得他们发生什么事了?   - 我不知道
- What do you think's happened to them?
- I don't know.
也许我们找到了门, 就能找到他们
Perhaps if we find that door, we'll find them.
快来, 你找那边, 我找这边
Come on. You take that end, I'll take this.
我们得快点
We must hurry.
Crossland 督察这会儿在牵制他们
Inspector Crossland's keeping them busy at the moment,
如果他用力过猛的话, 他不是他们的对手
but he'll be no match for them
if he presses them too far.
你会发现整架飞机都严格遵守国际航空安全标准
You'll find that the whole plane conforms strictly
to the international standards of air safety.
我想不会有任何人会投诉我们
I can't think why anybody would complain about us.
我说过有人投诉吗? 我不是来查安全措施的
Did I say anyone had complained?
I'm not enquiring about safety.
我来查的是一个失踪的男孩, 是你们航班的乘客
My enquiries are about a missing boy.
A passenger on one of your flights.
同时还有我的一个同事, Gascoigne 督察
And there's also the business of a colleague
of mine, Detective Inspector Gascoigne,
最后有人看见他也是在你们机库
was last seen in your hangar.
有人相信他已经被害了
He's believed to have been murdered.
这确实不是一件小事
That is indeed a serious matter.
恐怕我得让你推迟起飞一会儿
I'm afraid I'm going to have to ask you
to hold up this flight a while,
我有一些问题要问你
while I ask you some questions.
你介意来总指挥的办公室吗?
Would you mind coming to the commandant's office?
你得允许我失陪一下, 督察
If you'll just excuse me for a moment, Inspector,
我有些事情要安排
I have some arrangements to make.
- 抱歉, 请  - 对不起
- Excuse me, please.  - I'm sorry.
Blade 机长!
Captain Blade!
如果我是你, 就不会再移动一步
I shouldn't move any further if I were you.
这把枪在对付你的同事时非常有效, 那位 Gascoigne 督察
This gun proved remarkably effective
in dealing with your colleague, Inspector Gascoigne.
- 你杀了他  - 很不幸, 一个失误
- You killed him.  - Unfortunately, an error.
你们地球人活着对我们更有用
You Earth men are more use to us alive.
坐到那里去
Sit down there.
好多了
That's better.
这个地球人是个非常不错的标本, 你觉得呢?
This Earth man is a particularly
fine specimen, don't you think?
- 也许适合总管他自己  - 的确
- Perhaps the director himself.  - Exactly.
不管你俩计划把我怎么样
Whatever you two are planning for me,
我必须警告你, 这都在英国法律的长臂管辖内
I must warn you of the long arm of the British law.
我觉得它够不到你要去的地方
I don't think it will reach where you're going.
变色龙航班413呼叫塔台, 请求起飞
Chameleon Flight 4-1-3 to Control. Request start-up.
Jamie, 你看!
Jamie, look!
那是什么, 博士!
What's that, Doctor?
这是给不习惯地球空气的人准备的
For someone who's not used to the Earth's atmosphere.
很有意思
Very interesting.
啊! 一套视频监控设备. 我们来看看能看到什么
Ah! A TV monitor set. Let's see what we can see.
那是什么
What's that?
看起来像是个医院
It looks like a hospital.
Jamie, 这里有点热了
Jamie, we're getting warmer
这跟我上次在这里的情况有点不同
which is a change from the last time I was here!
快来, 我们去看看盖特威克机场有没有急救站
Come on. Let's see if there's
a first aid post in Gatwick airport.
- 我们要清理翻乱的东西吗, 博士?   - 不用
- Shall we clear up the mess, Doctor?  - No.
我们去找急救站
Let's get along to the first aid post.
噢, 我的背
Oh, my back!
Jamie, 我后背!
Jamie, my back!
请拿一个麦芽糖, 谢谢
Please take a barley sugar. Thank you.
你们可以解开安全带了, 谢谢
You can unfasten your seat belts now. Thank you.
麦芽糖要吗? 没事吧?
A barley sugar? Everything all right?
- 都搞定了 - 很好
- All set. - Good.
你不是想知道变色龙观光游的秘密吗?
You wanted to know what was the secret of Chameleon Tours.
好吧, 督察...
Well, Inspector...
你自己看
See for yourself.